EE471 û Modern Software Dev.                                                                      30/04/2026 
 
Izmir Institute of Technology 
Electrical and Electronics Eng. Dep. 
 
EE 471 Modern Software Development 
Practices and Technologies 
In-class exercise Week #9 
Thursday 30/04/2026 
Preliminary Task: Study the shared course materials Mediapipe solutions 
__________________________________________________________________________________________ 
Task 1: Choose 3 of the following vision tasks: Object detection, Image classification, Image 
segmentation, Hand landmark detection, Face landmark detection, and Pose landmark detection 
Read through their documentation, and demonstrate them in Python.  
Deliverables (Deadline: end of the lecture): 
1) The link for your public github repository 
2) A screen recording video demonstrating each of the tasks 
3) (Bonus) Complete all 6 of the tasks. 
__________________________________________________________________________________________ 
Task 2: Use a pose estimation library (e.g. mediapipe) to detect body pose in a given image, and 
write a script to classify which arm is up. Using Docker/cog containerize it. 
Input: $PATH-TO-INPUT-IMAGE, Output: ôleftö, ôrightö, ôbothö or ôNoneö  
Test your script with 3 input images provided: pose-1.jpg, pose-2.jpg, and pose-3.jpg.  
Task 3: Use a face detection library (e.g. mediapipe) to detect the face's looking direction in a 
given image, and write a script to classify if the face is looking towards left, right, or straight. Using 
Docker/cog containerize it. 
Input: $PATH-TO-INPUT-IMAGE, Output: ôleftö, ôrightö, or ôstraightö  
Test your script with 3 input images provided: face-1.png, face-2.png, and face-3.png.  
Deliverables (Deadline: until midnight):  
1) The link for your public github repository  
2) A screen recording video demonstrating each of the tasks 
3) A screen recording video with you explaining the purpose of each of the code blocks used 
(line by line not needed, but still try to explain thoroughly). 
